nihr.ac.uk 2016-05-09

# NIHR Privacy Policy

## NIHR privacy policy: how we use your information

This privacy policy sets out how the NIHR uses and protects any information that you give the NIHR when you use this website.

The NIHR is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

The NIHR may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from July 1, 2014.

### What we collect

We may collect the following information:

• name and job title  
• contact information including email address and host institution  
• information relevant to research award administration, management and evaluation.

### What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to provide one or more services, and in particular for the following reasons:

• Internal record keeping  
• Maintenance of peer reviewer database  
• Contact lists for media activities  
• Research monitoring and evaluation/analysis.

One or more of these services may be provided by a third party that will receive this information from the NIHR. Such third parties must handle your information in compliance with this privacy policy.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. We use leading technologies and encryption software to safeguard your data, and keep strict security standards to prevent any unauthorised access to it.

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Controlling your personal information

We will not sell or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to:

Freedom of information (FOI) requests  
Ministerial Correspondence and Public Enquiries Unit  
Department of Health  
Richmond House  
79 Whitehall  
London  
SW1A 2NS

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
